vevivos.com 2019-12-14

# Privacy Policy: GDPR and Data Protection Policy - Verily Victoria Vocalises

## Who we are

Our website address is: https://www.vevivos.com. My name is Victoria Welton and I am the owner of this blog.

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

In order to provide a user friendly experience on this blog, including but not limited to comments, social media interaction and giveaways, Verily Victoria Vocalises may process and retain information about an individual, either following the individual opting-in or on the basis of legitimate interest. Information that may be gathered will include name and contact details. We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting it. The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you what personally identifiable information we may collect and how it may be used. This statement only applies to this website.

I respect the privacy of all who visit this website, and will only collect and use personal data in ways that are described here, and in a way that is consistent with my obligations and your rights under the law.

### 

When visitors leave comments on this site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymised string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy [is available here](https://automattic.com/privacy/).  After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Contact forms and Subscribers to this blog

You may have completed a contact form or previously subscribed to this blog. Being on our database means that you may receive focused information from about posts or similar.

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. We do not store information we collect about your visit to this blog for use other than to analyse content performance through the use of cookies, which you can turn off at any time by modifying your Internet browser’s settings.

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your machine to help the site provide a better user experience. In general, cookies are used to retain user preferences and store information for things like comment forms, and provide anonymised tracking data to third party applications like Google Analytics.

As a rule, cookies will make your browsing experience better. However, you may prefer to disable cookies on this site. The most effective way to do this is to disable cookies in your browser. We suggest consulting the Help section of your browser or taking a look at the [About Cookies](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) website which offers guidance for all modern browsers

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website. Please note that we cannot be held responsible for anything related to this third-party tracking.

## 

We do not share any visitors personal information with third-parties nor do we store information we collect about your visit to this blog for use other than to analyse content performance through the use of cookies, which you can turn off at any time by modifying your Internet browser’s settings. Please see ‘Cookies’ section above.

If you have entered a giveaway or competition on this blog or via any of my social media platforms, you are automatically agreeing to potentially having your details passed on to a third party. ALL OF THE INFORMATION PROVIDED WILL BE DISPOSED OF BY ME ONCE THE COMPETITION OR GIVEAWAY HAS ENDED AND WILL NOT BE USED FOR ANY OTHER PURPOSES. Please note that I cannot be held responsible for what the third party does with your personal data.

We are not responsible for the republishing of the content found on this blog on other websites or media without our permission.

In some limited circumstances, we may be legally required to share certain personal data, which might include yours, if we are involved in legal proceedings or complying with legal obligations, a court order, or the instructions of a government authority.

### Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

### How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely and certainly for the life of this website. This is so we can recognise and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

### What rights you have over your data

Individuals retain the right to determine how they are contacted, the right for personal data to be removed from our records, the right to be forgotten by us, the right to view records or information held about them providing this request is not unfounded or excessive, and the right to have any erroneous information corrected.

At any point, an individual may opt-out of any form of communication with us. If you do not want to be on our database please let us know by emailing vickywelton@hotmail.com with OPT OUT as a subject line and we’ll take you out. Any requests will be effected within one calendar month of notification.

Further information about your rights can also be obtained from the Information Commissioner’s Office or your local Citizens Advice Bureau.

If you have any cause for complaint about my use of your personal data, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office.

## Display Adverts

We may use third-party advertising companies to serve content and advertisements when you visit their website, which may use cookies, as noted above. These include Google AdSense – you can click to view the [Google AdSense privacy policy here.](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites)

Please note that some third-party advertisers may collect their own tracking data.

## Retargeting Adverts

From time to time, the Website may engage in remarketing efforts with third-party companies, such as Google, Facebook, or Instagram, in order to market the content. These companies use cookies to serve ads based on someone’s past visits to the Website.

## Affiliate Program Participation

This Website may engage in affiliate marketing, which is done by embedding tracking links. If you click on a link for an affiliate partnership, a cookie will be placed on your browser to track any sales for purposes of commissions. This includes the Amazon Affiliate programme of which I am a member. You can view[ their privacy policy here](https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=468496#GUID-1B2BDAD4-7ACF-4D7A-8608-CBA6EA897FD3__SECTION_0D132936501A4AE0A2F8D74426A8A2CA). Please note that some of the adverts in the sidebar on this site are also part of an affiliation programme and this information also applies.

## Google Analytics 

My site uses analytics provided by Google Analytics. Website analytics refer to a set of tools used to collect and analyse how this site is used. This in turn enables us to improve this site and the services and experience offered through it.

The analytics service used by this site uses cookies to gather the required information. The use of cookies does not pose any risk to your privacy or your safety use of my site and you do not have to allow us to use them. However, it does enable us to continually improve this site, making it a better and more useful experience for you. You can view the [Google Analytics privacy policy here](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en).

## Changes to This Privacy Policy

We may change this Privacy Policy at any time. This may be necessary, for example, if the law changes, or if I change my business in a way that affects personal data protection.

Any changes will be immediately posted on this site and you will have automatically accepted these updated terms on your first use of this site following the update. It is down to the user to check this page regularly to ensure that they are up to date with the terms.

 **Last updated:  **24th May 2018
